

AZALEA VASEGHI

CREATIVE TECHNOLOGIST

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a graduate of NYU's Interactive Telecommunications Program and a hybrid interactive designer and developer. In total, I have six years experience using technology to create innovative and captivating new experiences. I am driven, resourceful, and have a passion for people.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

New York University

Interactive Telecommunications MPS, 2019

Parsons School of Design

Communication Design BFA, 2013

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Javascript | HTML | CSS | PHP | Java | Swift
Python | Arduino C | Git | Wordpress | Node.js
MongoDB | Express | Firebase | Jquery
Photoshop | After Effects | Illustrator
Premiere | Audition | Maya | Blender
Vectorworks | Eagle | Machine learning | AR

CONTACT

Mobile: 908-652-1111 Email: azaleavaseghi@gmail.com Portfolio: www.azaleavaseghi.com

WORK HISTORY

Freelance Interactive Designer

Various, 2017 - Present

- Ideated and designed branded augmented reality experiences
- Developed custom widgets using Wix's open development platform
- Developed interactive video installation using Javascript and Max to be exhibited at SXSW

Creative Technologist

Octagon, 2021

- Ideated experiential activations for sponsored sports events
- Researched and held a weekly presentation on the topic of emerging digital trends for the benefit of the Innovation team
- Designed and prototyped a marketing strategy tool for account managers that tracks venue capacity as COVID restrictions lifted
- Project managed a live digital conferencing event with over 50 speakers
- Coordinated with 3rd party vendors regarding project scope, budget, and timelines
- Provided account managers with proposals outlining the scope, budget, user experience, and timelines of potential emerging technology experiences for sponsored activations

Accessibility User Experience Designer

New York University 2018 -2019

- Audited site content to ensure compliance with WCAG 2.0/2.1 standards of Web Accessibility using tools such as VoiceOver and keyboard
- Logged accessibility issues uncovered by audits for developers along with suggested solutions to resolve said issues
- Consulted ITP teaching staff on web accessibility tools such as VoiceOver, JAWS, and NVDA and WCAG 2.0/2.1 standards and best practices to ensure future course site content compliance with WCAG 2.0/2.1 Web Accessibility standards

Summer Immersion Program Instructor

Girls Who Code, 2018

- Taught 20 high school students 5 different programming languages over the course of an intensive 7-week program.
- Monitored students' progress and provided guidance and insights on their projects.
- Delegated assignments and tasks to my teaching staff and coordinated classroom logistics.

Interactive Designer

Opera Browser, 2014 - 2016

- Ideated, designed, and developed advertising campaigns that leveraged cutting edge mobile technology to help connect brands with their consumers.
- Consulted members of sales, account management, and operations on the most recent advances in mobile technology and design to accommodate each clients' unique desires and needs.
- Worked with technical and non-technical individuals across agencies and teams to make each campaign a success.
- Created mock-ups for colleagues and clients, while also making edits and providing thoughtful solutions to challenges that would materialize through multiple rounds of approval.